A Guide to the Virginia Housing Study Commission Records, 1970-2004
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Housing Study Commission Records, 1970-2004
The Library of Virginia
41286
29 cubic feet
Virginia. Housing Study Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 41286 transferred by Nancy M. Ambler, Executive Director and Counsel, Virginia Housing Study Commmission, 601 S. Belvidere Street, Richmond, Va., 30 June 2004.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Housing Study Commission was established as an independent legislative agency by the Virginia General Assembly in April 1970. Rural and urban studies had previously found that substandard housing was a statewide problem. The Commission was ordered to "study and report its recommendations on the ways and means best designed to utilize existing resources and to develop facilities that will provide the Commonwealth's growing population with adequate housing." The Commission was initially comprised of 9 members, but the membership was later increased to 11, including five members of the House of Delegates, three members of the Senate and three gubernatorial appointees. The Commission's existence was continued by Act of Assembly in 1972, 1974 and 1976. The Commission worked to establish the Virginia Housing Development Authority (VHDA), aided in the passage of the Virginia Residential Landlord and Tenant Act, helped pass the Uniform Statewide Building Code, and worked to ensure public building accessibility to disabled persons. The Commission also helped start the Virginia Housing Partnership Fund and the Virginia Indoor Plumbing Program.
A motion to collapse the operations of the Virginia Housing Study Commission into the Department of Legislative Services was presented and passed at the June 8, 2004 meeting of the Commission. The Virginia Housing Study Commission ceased to exist as an independent agency on June 30, 2004, with Nancy M. Ambler serving as the last executive director. Once under the heading of the Department of Legislative Services, the name was changed to the Virginia Housing Commission. The Commission still studies housing policy and continues to make recommendations to the General Assembly relating to housing, real property and community development issues.
Scope and Content
Contains mostly correspondence and subject files relating to the operations and activities of the Virginia Housing Study Commission. The material was created and used by Nancy M. Amber, Executive Director and Counsel, and her assistant, Nancy Blanchard. Included are annual reports, budget information, project files, meeting notes, publications and legislative material. Also included in this collection are electronic records (email and other documents on compact disks), photographs, and audio tapes. The records pertain to a variety of housing-related subjects, including the Virginia Housing Partnership Fund, landlord-tenant relations, eminent domain, public hearings on housing issues, homelessness, and predatory lending. Many of the records are still housed in their original binders. There is some duplication of files between the two series, so it would benefit the researcher to examine the content lists for both series.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files (Executive Director, Nancy Ambler), 1970-2004
Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files (Assistant, Nancy Blanchard), 1971-2004
The physical arrangement of the collection has been maintained, but arrangement in the finding aid is alphabetical by folder title. (A box-by-box folder list is available in the receipt file).
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files (Executive Director, Nancy Ambler), 1970-2004., Extent: 25 cubic feet. (Box 1-15; 20-29)
  - AAD, 1994. (Box 5)
  - AAD (Certificates of Appreciation), undated. (Box 18, 29)
  - AAD (William and Mary Remarks), undated. (Box 18)
  - "A Blue Print for Action," 1998. (Box 21)
  - Abandoned/Vacant Housing, 1993. (Box 7)
  - "A Decent Place to Live," 1988. (Box 20)
  - Adequacy of Community Association Reserve Funds, undated. (Box 11)
  - Adoption Statistics, 1999. (Box 3)
  - Affordable Housing (Georgia), 1988. (Box 20)
  - Affordable Housing Impact Statements, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Affordable Housing Summit, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Agenda, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Agenda, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Alexandria Landlord Tenant Study, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Ambler Articles, undated. (Box 29)
  - Ambler Correspondence, 1987-1989. (Box 18, 29)
  - Ambler Speeches, 1987-1993. (Box 18, 29)
  - Annual Meeting, 1979. (Box 13)
  - Annual Meeting, 1990. (Box 15)
  - Annual Meeting at The Homestead, 1981. (Box 14)
  - Annual Meeting at The Homestead, 1982. (Box 14)
  - Annual Report, 1979. (Box 14)
  - Annual Report, 1987. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1987-1988. (Box 14)
  - Annual Report, 1988. (Box 14)
  - Annual Report, 1989. (Box 15)
  - Annual Report, 1990. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1991. (Box 15, 26)
  - Annual Report, 1992. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1993. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1994. (Box 6, 26)
  - Annual Report, 1995. (Box 5, 21, 26)
  - Annual Report, 1996. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1997. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1998. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 1999. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 2000. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 2001. (Box 26)
  - Annual Report, 2002. (Box 11, 26, 28)
  - Annual Report (Binder), 2002. (Box 29)
  - Annual Report, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Annual Report (Binder), 2003. (Box 29)
  - Annual Report (Distribution), 1992. (Box 8)
  - Annual Report (Distribution Letters), 2003. (Box 10)
  - Annual Report (Distribution Letters), 2004. (Box 10)
  - Annual Report (Distribution List), 1993. (Box 7)
  - Annual Report (Letters), 1992. (Box 7)
  - Annual Report (Letters), 2002. (Box 10)
  - Annual Report (Letters), 2003. (Box 10)
  - Annual Report (Letters and Memos), 1994. (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1988-2003. (Box 29)
  - Assemblies for Action, 1993. (Box 21)
  - Assisted Living 1997. (Box 3)
  - Assisted Living, Affordable, Subcommittee on, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Assisted Living, Affordable, Subcommittee on, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Assisted Living Tour, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Attendance Sheets (Notepads), undated. (Box 14)
  - Audit, 1994 FY. (Box 5)
  - Budget, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Budget Amendments, 1994. (Box 5)
  - Budget and Thank-you Letters, 2002. (Box 10)
  - CAI Information, undated. (Box 12)
  - CDBG, undated. (Box 29)
  - CHAS (Annual Performance Report), undated. (Box 21)
  - Cities Commission, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Commission Appointments, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Committee Meetings, 1978-1979. (Box 13)
  - Common Interest (Facts), undated. (Box 12)
  - Common Interest, Subcommittee on, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Community Assistance (Binder), 1999. (Box 15)
  - Community Association Reserve Funds, 2002; 2004. (Box 21)
  - Community Associations, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Community Land Trust Study, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy, 1993. (Box 7)
  - Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy, 1994. (Box 7)
  - Comprehensive Housing Affordability Strategy, 1996. (Box 7)
  - Condemnation, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Condo Act, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Condo Act Subcommittee, 1991-1992. (Box 8)
  - Condo Super Liens Study, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Consolidated Plan, 1996-2000. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1977. (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1981. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1992. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1993. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1994. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1995. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1996. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1997. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1999. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2000. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2002. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2003. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 2004 FY. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Memos, 1988. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence and Memos, 1989. (Box 14)
  - Correspondence (Ritchie, John), 1987. (Box 14)
  - COSCAA Newsletters, 1987-1989. (Box 20)
  - COSCAA Publications, various dates. (Box 20)
  - Decent and Affordable Housing for All (NGA), 1986. (Box 20)
  - DHCD Board, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Diamonstein Articles, undated. (Box 29)
  - Diamonstein Correspondence, 1988-1989. (Box 18, 29)
  - Diamonstein Speeches (Housing), undated. (Box 18, 29)
  - Diamonstein Speeches (Other than Housing), undated. (Box 18, 29)
  - Disability Commission, undated. (Box 10)
  - Disability Commission (Housing), undated. (Box 11)
  - Drake, Thelma, Issues, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Dwoski Issue, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Economic Growth and Affordable Housing, 2001. (Box 11)
  - E-mail and Electronic Records (Compact Disk), 1991-2004. (Box Erecs Box 1)
  - Eminent Domain, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Fair Housing, 2002. (Box 10)
  - "Finding Shelter: The Growing Housing Crisis in Virginia," 1987. (Box 20)
  - FNMA (Orange Workshop), 2002. (Box 10)
  - "Following the Blueprint," 1992. (Box 21)
  - GCH, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1988. (Box 9)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1993. (Box 7)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1994. (Box 6)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, 1999. (Box 2)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing (Audio Tapes), 1989(?). (Box 20)
  - Growth Management, undated. (Box 29)
  - HB 501, 1994. (Box 6)
  - HB 622, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 780, 1993. (Box 6)
  - HB 822 (Public Use), undated. (Box 10)
  - HB 827, 2004. (Box 10)
  - HB 933, undated. (Box 12)
  - HB 1145, undated. (Box 12)
  - HB 1174, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1204, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1205, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1206, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1235, 1994. (Box 6)
  - HB 1238, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1245 (Fair Housing), undated. (Box 10)
  - HB 1251 (Dissolution of), 1996. (Box 4)
  - HB 1261, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HB 1322 (Cable Access Subcommittee), 1996. (Box 4)
  - HB 1381, 1994. (Box 6)
  - HB ? (Foreclosure), undated. (Box 10)
  - HJR 161, 1996. (Box 4)
  - HJR 173 (Indoor Plumbing), undated. (Box 11)
  - HJR 192, 1994. (Box 6)
  - HJR 198, 1992-1996. (Box 4)
  - HJR 208, 1997-1998. (Box 3)
  - HJR 236, 2000. (Box 12)
  - HJR 251, 1994. (Box 5)
  - HJR 253, undated. (Box 12)
  - HJR 254 (Home Ownership), undated. (Box 12)
  - HJR 272 (Water Commission), 1998. (Box 13)
  - HJR 442 (Fire Retardant Treated Plywood), 1993. (Box 7)
  - HJR 554, 1997. (Box 3)
  - HJR 570, 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 570, 1995-1996. (Box 4)
  - HJR 570 (Expansive Soil Information), 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 570 (Press Clippings), 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 570 (Shrink Swell Soil Study), 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 570 (Summary of Testimony), 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 570 (Task Force Evaluation), 1995. (Box 5)
  - HJR 731, 1999. (Box 2)
  - HJR 739 / HB 1454, 1999. (Box 2)
  - HJR 744, 1999. (Box 2)
  - HJR 746, 1999. (Box 2)
  - HJR 747, 1999. (Box 2)
  - HJR 747 (Public Awareness), undated. (Box 12)
  - HJR 749, 1999. (Box 2)
  - Home Ownership, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Home Ownership, 2001. (Box 11-12)
  - Homelessness Conference, 1993. (Box 7)
  - Homelessness in Virginia (FY 1990-1991), 1992. (Box 8, 21)
  - Homelessness Study, 1992-1993. (Box 8)
  - House of Delegates Documents, undated. (Box 9)
  - Housing Commission Study, undated. (Box 13)
  - "Housing Crisis" Publication, 1970 (?). (Box 27)
  - Housing Forums, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Housing Investment Patterns in Richmond, 1979. (Box 20)
  - Housing Legislation, 1993-1994. (Box 5)
  - Housing Rally, 1994. (Box 5)
  - Housing Roundtable, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Housing Study Commission, 1983. (Box 14)
  - Indoor Plumbing Program, undated. (Box 29)
  - Interim Meeting, 2002. (Box 10)
  - Interim Meeting (Binder), 2002. (Box 28)
  - Interim Meeting, 2003. (Box 10)
  - "Introduction to Real Estate and Real Estate Financing," 1989. (Box 21)
  - Invoices, 1996. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 1997. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 1998. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 1999. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 2001. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 2002. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 2003. (Box 2)
  - Invoices, 2004. (Box 2)
  - JLARC Final Report (VHDA), 2000. (Box 20)
  - JLARC Final Report (VHDA), 2001. (Box 20)
  - JLARC (VHDA), 1985. (Box 20)
  - Joint Audit and Review Commission, VAHA Report, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Land Trusts, 1995-1996. (Box 5)
  - Landlord-Tenant Act, 1996-1997. (Box 4)
  - Landlord-Tenant Act Update, 1998-1999. (Box 3)
  - Landlord-Tenant Issues, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Landlord Tenant Law, 1993-1994. (Box 5)
  - Lead-based Paint, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Legal Seminar, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Legislation, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Legislation, 1993-1994. (Box 5)
  - Legislation, 2002. (Box 11)
  - Legislation, 2004. (Box 10)
  - Legislation to be Introduced, 1993-1994. (Box 5)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 1995. (Box 26)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 1996. (Box 26)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 1998. (Box 28)
  - Legislative Meeting, 1999. (Box 2)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 1999. (Box 28)
  - Legislative Meeting, 2001. (Box 12)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 2001. (Box 28)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 2002. (Box 28)
  - Legislative Meeting (Binder), 2003. (Box 29)
  - Legislative Summary, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Legislative Summary, 1993. (Box 6)
  - Legislative Summary, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Legislative Summary, 1997. (Box 4)
  - Legislative Summary, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1987. (Box 23)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1988. (Box 23)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1989. (Box 23)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1990. (Box 24)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binders), 1991. (Box 24, 27)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binders), 1992. (Box 24, 27)
  - Legislative Work Session, 1992-1993. (Box 8)
  - Legislative Work Session, 1993. (Box 7)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binders), 1993. (Box 25, 27)
  - Legislative Work Session, 1994. (Box 6)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1994. (Box 25)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1995. (Box 25)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1996. (Box 25)
  - Legislative Work Session, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binders), 1997. (Box 22, 27)
  - Legislative Work Session, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1998. (Box 22)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 1999. (Box 22)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 2000. (Box 22)
  - Legislative Work Session (Binder), 2001. (Box 22)
  - Legislative Work Session (Photographs), 1994. (Box 6)
  - Lien/Foreclosure Legislation, 1994. (Box 6)
  - LIHPRHA Summaries, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Local Governments and Housing Policy Statewide, undated. (Box 10)
  - Long Term Care, 1992-1993. (Box 8)
  - Manufactured Housing, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Manufactured Housing, 2002; 2004. (Box 21)
  - Manufactured Housing, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Maryland Housing Commission Report, 1985. (Box 20)
  - Maryland Housing Commission Report, 1986. (Box 20)
  - Maryland Housing Commission Report, 1987. (Box 20)
  - Meeting, 2004. (Box 10)
  - Meeting Attendance, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Meeting Attendance, 2002. (Box 10)
  - Meeting Attendance, 2003. (Box 29)
  - Meeting Attendance, 2004. (Box 10)
  - Meeting/Dinner, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Meetings and Distribution, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Memos, 1987. (Box 14)
  - MFD Housing, 2001. (Box 11)
  - MF Education and Licensing, 1997. (Box 3)
  - MF Security Deposit Issue, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous House Documents, undated. (Box 9)
  - Mission Statement Development Study, 2004. (Box 10)
  - MLBA, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Mortgage Lending Practices, 1993-1995. (Box 6)
  - Mortgage Subcommittee, 1979. (Box 13)
  - Navy Housing, 1996. (Box 4)
  - NCCUSL/Non-judicial Foreclosure, undated. (Box 11)
  - New Building Products, 2001. (Box 12)
  - New Building Products, 2002. (Box 10)
  - New Building Products and Legislation, 2001. (Box 12)
  - Non-profit Organization Summit, 1994. (Box 6)
  - Non-profit Study, 1994. (Box 6)
  - NOVA Condo Testimony, 1992. (Box 8)
  - Occupancy Rates, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Olmstead, 2002. (Box 10)
  - Organizational Meeting, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Organizational Meeting (Binder), 2000. (Box 28)
  - Organizational Meeting, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Organizational Meeting (Binders), 2001. (Box 26, 28)
  - Organizational Meeting, 2002. (Box 10)
  - Organizational Meeting (Binder), 2002. (Box 28)
  - Organizational Meeting, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Organizational Meeting (Binder), 2003. (Box 28)
  - Organizational Meeting, 2004. (Box 10)
  - Organizational Meeting Announcement, 2003. (Box 10)
  - Organizational Meeting Preparation, 2004. (Box 10)
  - Original Housing Study Commission Study Topics, undated. (Box 9)
  - Originals, undated. (Box 11)
  - Partnership, Friends and HJR 760, 1997-1999. (Box 3)
  - Pennsylvania Economic Development Partnership, 1990. (Box 20)
  - Photographs, 1991. (Box 15, 29)
  - Photographs, 1999. (Box 29)
  - Photographs, undated. (Box 29)
  - Predatory Lending, 2002. (Box 11-12)
  - Predatory Lending (Binder), 2002. (Box 21)
  - Predatory Lending, undated. (Box 11)
  - Predatory Lending/Self Help (Background), undated. (Box 12)
  - Presentation VAHC DO, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Proceedings of Inner-city Lending, 1977. (Box 13)
  - Proposed Budget (FY 1996-1998), 1996. (Box 21)
  - Proposed Budget (FY 1998-2000), 1998. (Box 21)
  - Proposed Budget (FY 2000-2002), 2000. (Box 21)
  - Proposed Budget (FY 2002-2004), 2002. (Box 21)
  - Proposed Budget (FY 2004-2006), 2004. (Box 21)
  - Public Hearing, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Public Hearing, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Public Hearing (Leesburg), 1994. (Box 5)
  - Public Hearing (Newport News), 1994. (Box 5)
  - Public Hearing (Richmond), 1994. (Box 5)
  - Public Hearing (Virginia Housing Study Commission), 1995. (Box 5)
  - Public Hearing (Wise), 1994. (Box 6)
  - Public Hearings, 1992. (Box 7-8)
  - Public Hearings, 1993. (Box 6-7)
  - R 11 and R 12 Issue (Norfolk), undated. (Box 10)
  - Radon, 1998. (Box 3)
  - Real Estate Closings, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Real Property Issues, Subcommittee on, 1997. (Box 3)
  - Redemption Clarification, 1997-1998. (Box 3)
  - Remarks, 1999. (Box 3)
  - Rent-to-Own Contracts, 2002. (Box 10)
  - Report on Homelessness in the Commonwealth, 1992 FY. (Box 21)
  - Revitalization, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Robert Wood Johnson Project, 2000. (Box 2)
  - RTO, 2002. (Box 11)
  - RTOKs, 2002. (Box 11)
  - Rural Homelessness, 2000. (Box 13)
  - Rural Homelessness, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Rural Housing, 2000. (Box 13)
  - Rural Housing Issues, undated. (Box 29)
  - Rural Housing Meeting, 2000. (Box 13)
  - Sale of Portfolio, 2003. (Box 10)
  - SB 97, 1994. (Box 6)
  - SB 250 / HJR 8 (Water/Sewer Fees and Property Owner Associations), 1996. (Box 4)
  - SB 358, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SB 431, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SB 585, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SB 586, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SB 602, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SB 721 (Association Issues), undated. (Box 12)
  - SB 997 (Subordinate Mortgages), undated. (Box 11)
  - SB 1102 (Fair Housing Bill), undated. (Box 11)
  - SB 1493 (Lambert), undated. (Box 11)
  - Session Summary, 1999. (Box 3)
  - SJR 94, 1994. (Box 5)
  - SJR 115, 1998. (Box 3)
  - SJR 394, 1999. (Box 2)
  - State Housing Plan, 1978-1979. (Box 13)
  - State Housing Plan, 1980. (Box 14)
  - State of the Nation's Housing, 1988. (Box 20)
  - State of the Nation's Housing, 1989. (Box 20)
  - Study Agenda, 1996-1997. (Box 4)
  - Subdivision Street Standards, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Task Force Study (Virginia Eviction Procedures), 1993. (Box 7)
  - Tenant Management Study, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Thank-yous, 2003. (Box 10)
  - "The Housing Crisis," undated. (Box 9)
  - "Toward a National Housing Policy," 1987. (Box 20)
  - Unlicensed Home Improvement, 1996. (Box 4)
  - VFHP/Visitability, 2004. (Box 10)
  - VHC-KS, 1997. (Box 3)
  - VHDA Files (John Ritchie), 1977. (Box 13)
  - Virginia Association of Housing (HUD Fair Housing Seminar), 2003. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Commission on Youth, 1996-1997. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Commission on Youth (HJR 181), 1996-1997. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition, undated. (Box 11)
  - Virginia Housing Conference, 2000. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Housing Conference, 2001. (Box 11)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership, 1993 FY. (Box 21)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership, undated. (Box 21)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership (Training), 1992-1993. (Box 21)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund, 1999-2000. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund, undated. (Box 21)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund (Allocations), 1988-1997. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund (Annual Report), 1989. (Box 21)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund (Production Reports), 1997. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Housing Partnership Fund (Report), 2000. (Box 13)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission, 1980. (Box 14)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Agenda), 2000. (Box 12)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Annual Session: Building Regulatory Issues), 1982. (Box 9)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Annual Session: Eminent Domain Issues), 1982. (Box 9)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Annual Session: Housing Issues), 1982. (Box 9)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Annual Work Session), 1979. (Box 9)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Audio Tapes), undated. (Box 9)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Legislation), 2000. (Box 12)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Legislative Meeting), 1997. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Ritchie, John), 1987. (Box 14)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Subcommittees), 2000. (Box 12)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Summary), 2000. (Box 12)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission (Testimony: Ritchie, John), 1988. (Box 14)
  - Virginia Housing Study Commission Workshop, 1978. (Box 13)
  - Water and Mobile Homes, 1992. (Box 7)
  - Week of the Long Term Care Giver, 1999. (Box 3)
  - WG, 2001. (Box 11)
  - WIS Invitation, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Work Group, 2000. (Box 12)
  - Work Group, undated. (Box 12)
  - Work Plan, 1993. (Box 6)
  - Work Programs (State Board of Housing), 1976-1977. (Box 13)
  - Work Session, 1976. (Box 13)
  - Work Session, 1978. (Box 13)
  - Work Session, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Work Session, 1996. (Box 4)
  - Work Session Agenda, 1981. (Box 14)
  - Work Session Meeting (Binder), 1987. (Box 26)
  - Work Session Meeting (Binder), 1989. (Box 26)
  - Workbook, 1995. (Box 5)
  - Workbook for Work Session, 1982. (Box 14)
  - Unlabled Folders, undated. (Box 3)
  - Urban Partnership, 1995. (Box 5)
- Series II. Correspondence and Subject Files (Assistant, Nancy Blanchard), 1971-2004., Extent: 4 cubic feet. (Box 16-19.)
  - Acts of Assembly, undated. (Box 18)
  - Air Conditioning Regulations, undated. (Box 17)
  - Almand Commission, undated. (Box 18)
  - Annual Report, 1995-2000. (Box 16)
  - Annual Report, 2001. (Box 16)
  - Annual Report (Correspondence), 2001. (Box 16)
  - ARA Catering, undated. (Box 16)
  - Archives Folder, undated. (Box 16)
  - Assisted Living, Subcommittee on, 1997-1998. (Box 17)
  - Biographical Sketches (Alan Diamonstein and Nancy Ambler), undated. (Box 16)
  - Budget, 1988-1992. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 1994-1996. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 1996-1998. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 1998-2000. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 2000-2002. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 2001 FY. (Box 18)
  - Budget, 2003. (Box 18)
  - Budget (2004-2006), 2004. (Box 18)
  - Budget for Housing Programs, 1994-1996. (Box 16)
  - Budget Negotiation, 2002. (Box 18)
  - Commission Activities, 1987. (Box 16)
  - Elevator Safety, 2003. (Box 16)
  - E-mail and Electronic Records (Compact Disk), 1991-2004. (Box Erecs Box 1)
  - Governor's Conference on Housing, undated. (Box 16)
  - HB 501 and HB 1381, undated. (Box 17)
  - HB 606 (Community Association Issues), undated. (Box 16)